<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
    xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0">
    <channel>
        <title>bt-trx</title>
        <atom:link href="https://bt-trx.com//en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <link>https://bt-trx.com//en/</link>
        <description>Connect your HAM radio or CB radio wirelessly to your car using Bluetooth! Verbinde dein Amateurfunk oder CB Funkgerät über Bluetooth mit dem Auto!</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 21:48:20 +0200</pubDate>
        <webfeeds:icon>https://bt-trx.com//en/assets/img/bt-trx_quadrat.svg</webfeeds:icon>
        
        <item>
            
            <title>Release of dev-board v4.1 - Kits available!</title>
            <link>https://bt-trx.com//en/2019/10/07/release_dev-board_v4.1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">//en/2019/10/07/release_dev-board_v4.1.html</guid>
            <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;release-of-dev-board-v41---kits-available&quot;&gt;Release of dev-board v4.1 - Kits available!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dev-board-v41&quot;&gt;dev-board v4.1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last weeks we have been intensively working on the completion of the
board versions v4 and v4.1.
Actually it should be v4 which we also offer as a kit,
however, there have been short-term problems with the availability of the
ESP32 module used there. Therefore we had to rework the layout,
which resulted in v4.1.
This has the advantage that we have even more improvements in the version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work on the firmware for the ESP32 was also very successful.
It is now possible to use the PTT button to set up the telephone call.
and to install firmware updates via the WLAN of ESP32.
Version v0.1.3 will be shipped with the first kits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kits-available&quot;&gt;Kits available&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we are happy to announce that there is a first, limited edition
of the bt-trx kits in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.thinkstack.de&quot;&gt;thinkstack Shop&lt;/a&gt;
available for ordering. The kits will be shipped within the next 3 weeks.
We want to collect experiences of the first users and improve the
documentation in order to make it as easy as possible for a wider range
of users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/bt-trx/dev-board/raw/master/images/3d_view.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
dev-board v4.1&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            
            <title>Project Update August 2019</title>
            <link>https://bt-trx.com//en/2019/08/13/update_august_2019.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">//en/2019/08/13/update_august_2019.html</guid>
            <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;project-update-august-2019&quot;&gt;Project Update August 2019&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;firmware&quot;&gt;Firmware&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our latest tests with the new configuration parameters for the WT32i 
Bluetooth module were very successful. It is now possible to connect
also with radios of current vehicle models by e.g. VW and Ford without any problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have also been improvements in the detection of incoming connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these changes can be found in the firmware version &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bt-trx/firmware/releases/tag/0.1.2&quot;&gt;0.1.2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hardware&quot;&gt;Hardware&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fourth version of the bt-trx development board (“dev-board v4”) is now finished 
and prototypes are being produced.
The most significant change is the use of ESP32 as the controller, 
but there were also other changes made to make the board as simple and cheap as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If everything goes according to plan, this will also be the version that we’ll supply
as a kit. Currently it is planned to offer the kit from the beginning of October on &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.thinkstack.de&quot;&gt;shop.thinkstack.de&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
Probably we will take preorders starting from September, so its worthwile to have a look from time to time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2019-08-13_dev-board-v4-3d.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
3D Rendering dev-board v4&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            
            <title>Next steps</title>
            <link>https://bt-trx.com//en/2019/07/10/next_steps.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">//en/2019/07/10/next_steps.html</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a small update on the progress of the project&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;firmware&quot;&gt;Firmware&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, we had the opportunity again to test the current version of the
bt-trx firmware (0.1.0) with further radio models. It turns out that
accessory radios usually work without problems. Some manufacturer radios, on
the other hand, cannot currently be connected.
We already have a few configuration values of the WT32i Bluetooth module that
should fix this problem and will do some tests soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hardware&quot;&gt;Hardware&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently in the process of developing the fourth version of the bt-trx
development board.
The most significant change is that instead of the Teensy 3.2 module, we’ll switch
to an ESP32.
This is mainly because the ESP32 will cost about half of the price of the
Teensy module. As a further advantage, the ESP32 offers integrated
Wifi, which we may use in the future for configuration and firmware updates
of the bt-trx. With the integrated Bluetooth LE we can e.g.
wirelessly connect a PTT button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as we are finished with the development of v4, we will get started to 
make bt-trx kits available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            
            <title>Success at HAM RADIO 2019!</title>
            <link>https://bt-trx.com//en/2019/07/02/success_at_hamradio.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">//en/2019/07/02/success_at_hamradio.html</guid>
            <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;bt-trx-wins-the-1st-prize-at-the-ham-radio-2019&quot;&gt;bt-trx wins the 1st prize at the HAM RADIO 2019!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the HAM RADIO 2019 the &lt;a href=&quot;https://darc.de&quot;&gt;DARC e.V.&lt;/a&gt; announced the winner of the
“Handsfree Building Competition”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, we had a great time at the DARC VUS booth during the day (Thanks to DG8NGN!),
where we had the opportunity to present and explain bt-trx to the visitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2019-06-22_HAMRADIO01.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The award ceremony took place at 17:00 on the main stage. The five participants of the competition had the opportunity to present their projects to the audience and to the jury.
The jury consisted among others of the DARC board members Werner Bauer, DJ2ET
and Christian Entsfellner, DL3MBG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bt-trx was finally able to assert itself against the other projects and
was chosen as the winner by the jury. The jury particularly praised the advanced
development stage and the focus on cost-effective reproducibility of the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 1st prize was awarded with a voucher of 150 € for the DARC Verlag Shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2019-06-22_HAMRADIO02.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Andreas Müller, DC1MIL with the main prize&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            
            <title>bt-trx at HAM RADIO 2019</title>
            <link>https://bt-trx.com//en/2019/05/22/hamradio-2019.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">//en/2019/05/22/hamradio-2019.html</guid>
            <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;presentation-of-bt-trx-at-the-ham-radio-2019-in-friedrichshafen&quot;&gt;Presentation of bt-trx at the HAM RADIO 2019 in Friedrichshafen&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motivated by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://darc.de&quot;&gt;DARC e.V.&lt;/a&gt; “Handsfree construction competition” we have developed the bt-trx for all radio amateurs and CB radio operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hamradio-friedrichshafen.de&quot;&gt;HAM RADIO 2019&lt;/a&gt; in Friedrichshafen the award ceremony for the competition participants will take place. Besides the event on the DARC stage on Saturday 22.06.2019 at 17:00 we can also be found on the HAM RADIO for the whole weekend. There you can try out the bt-trx and enter into dialogue with the developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>